By taking the knowledge that we learned about overriding
the resources in the other folders we'll walk through the
code together on how to build up the two-pane tablet
UI. First remove the values w820dp folder because we don't
need to provide specific logic for where the current
orientation is greater than 820 dp. Then go ahead and
make the layout XML changes. Then create a new layout
swe600dp folder, and then add a new file called activity_main.
We use the same file and name as in
the base layout folder activity_main, so that this one
overrides the behavior, specifically on tablets. To see the
code for this file, you can check out the gist
below. Essentially it's a horizontal linear layout that can
hold forecast fragment on the left, and the detail fragment
on the right. Now's a good time to talk
about static versus dynamic fragments. In our implementation, the forecast
fragment is a static fragment because we're defining it the XML
layout. No matter what orientation or device size, we know that
we're going to need a forecast fragment in the main activity. On
the other hand, we only need to declare a container for
the detail fragment, but not the actual fragment. It's initialized with
different arguments each time, as a dynamic fragment, so it's better
to dynamically create and add that fragment in a fragment transaction
in the main activity Java code. That way the fragment manager
can keep track of those initialization arguments and pass those
back to us after device rotation. Then we need to update
the one pane UI layouts so that they are consistent with
the two pane case. So in the activity_main file for the
base layout folder, this used to be a frame layout. We're
going to declare it as a forecast fragment, that way it will
match the two pin UI where this is also declared as
a fragment in the XML. That way the main activity never
has to worry about dynamically adding the forecast fragment.
And the main activity onCreate view method, since the
fragment is already inside this layout we can just
remove this so we don't dynamically add it again. Similar,
we've modified the activity_detail layout in the base layout
folder. We change the frame that ID, to be
weather detail container; so that it matches the container
view ID in the two pane UI case,. The pattern
here is that the detail fragment will always be
added to a container called weather_detail_container, both in the two
pane and one pane case. Since we changed the name
of the container we should also update the DetailActivity. This
is only used in one pane mode. Here's where we
change the container name. In the one pane mode, the
DetailActivity will add the DetailFragment, dynamically to this container. After
we modify the layout we should update the main activities,
that we dynamically add the DetailFragment. In the MainActivity
onCreate method, we check for the presence of the weather_detail_container
in the layout to know whether this is a two
pane UI or not. We keep track of this information
in a bullion called mTwoPane. Remember that we start with
the letter M because it's a member variable. In this
case, the bullion should be true. So we go ahead
and create a DetailFragment and add it to the weather_detail_container.
We commit the change by using a fragment transaction, which
Rato introduced earlier. Otherwise, if the detail container is not
present in the layout, then the boolean should be false,
meaning that this is a one pane UI for phones.
In this case, the detail activity will handle showing the
detail fragment. Notice for the two pane case that we
check, if the savedInstanceState bundle is null. If the savedInstanceState
bundle is not null, then we don't create a new one.
And here's the reason why. Say, you want to rotate
the device. Before the activity and fragments get torn down,
we store information in saved state bundles. Then after the
orientation change, the system restores the activity and the fragments
by passing back the same bundle so that it can
be re-created with the same state. That means if the
bundle exists then we should let the system handle restoring
the detail fragment and we can skip this code. Once the
detail fragment is added dynamically make it show some placeholder
data just for testing purposes. Later we'll plumb through the right
logic so that it can display the right information for
the selected date on the left. Modify the DetailFragment so that
it doesn't expect the incoming intent to have the DATE_KEY.
In this case it doesn't start the loader, which is fine,
and it just falls back to some placeholder data that we
have in our XML. The same goes for the onResume method.
We don't restart the loader if the intent is blank.
The reason the Intent could be blank, is because the detail
fragment can now exist within the main activity. So the main
activity doesn't have the same Intent key, that the DetailActivity was
launched with. Once you make the changes for the wireframes,
this is what the app should look like. The reason it
doesn't show an icon here is because we removed the icon
from being hardcoded in the layout. But once this data's populated
dynamically in a later section, it should show up again.